Inventory of David D. Laitin papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1966-2006 (Box 7-12)
  - Somali Horizon, Nos. 4-6, 1986 (Box-folder 10: 17)
    Scope and Contents note
    Monthly magazine of the Somali National Movement (SNM).
  - "Somali Manifesto,", undated (Box-folder 10: 18)
  - "Somali Maritime History and Regional Diversity: An Introduction," draft, Geshekter, Charles L., 1991 (Box-folder 10: 19)
  - "The Somali Opposition Fronts: Some Comments and Questions," Campagnon, Daniel, undated (Box-folder 10: 20)
  - "An Overview of Somali's Experience and Strategy in Rural Development," Somali Unit for Research on Emergencies and Rural Development (SURERD), undated (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - "Somalia: Background Information for Operation Restore Hope, 1992-1993," Clarke, Walter S. (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - "Somalia in Colliers Encyclopedia,", undated (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - Somalia NGO Consortium, 2003 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - "Somalia on the Brink of Civil War," Warsama, Mohammed, 1983 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - "Somalia: The Case of Triage," Stedman, John Stephen, 1992 (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - "Changing Realities in the Horn of Africa: Implications for Africa and U.S. Foreign Policy," Stanley Foundation, 1991 October (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - Statement before the House Sub-Committee on Africa, Adelman, Kenneth L., 1981 (Box-folder 11: 8)
  - Statement before the House Sub-Committee on Africa, Harbeson, John W., 1981 (Box-folder 11: 9)
  - Statement before the House Committee on Appropriation, Crocker, Chester A., 1983 (Box-folder 11: 10)
  - "Strategy on Somalia,", undated (Box-folder 11: 11)
  - Syncrisis: The Dynamics of Health, "An Analytic Series on the Interactions of Health and Socioeconomic Development: Somalia," draft, undated (Box-folder 11: 12)
  - Testimony of Assistant Secretary of State for African Affairs, Cohen, Herman J., 1992 December 17 (Box-folder 11: 13)
  - Third International Congress of Somali Studies, Rome, Italy, 1986 May 26-31 (Box-folder 11: 14)
  - ABC's This Week with David Brinkley, "Somalia," transcript, 1992 December 6 (Box-folder 11: 15)
  - CBS's Face the Nation, "Somalia," transcript, 1992 December 6 (Box-folder 11: 16)
  - NBC's Today Show, "Somalia," transcript, 1992 December 6 (Box-folder 11: 17)
  - "The Transitional Federal Charter of the Somali Republic,", 2004 February (Box-folder 11: 18)
  - "The United Nations and the Collective Use of Force," Ruggie, John Gerard, 1996 (Box-folder 11: 19)
  - "Somalia," draft resolution, U.N. Security Council, 1992 December 3 (Box-folder 11: 20)
  - "The U.S. Military Role in Somalia," Pentagon Briefing Room, 1992 December 4 (Box-folder 11: 21)
  - "Somalia," U.S. State Department briefings, undated (Box-folder 11: 22)
  - "United States Policy Towards the Horn of Africa: The Balance of External and Regional Interests," draft, Habtesellasie, Bereket, 1983 (Box-folder 11: 23)
  - "Somalia," Westview Press editorial style sheet, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - "Why Somalis Flee: Synthesis of Accounts of Conflict Experience in Northern Somalia by Somali Refugees, Displaced Persons and Others," Gersony, Robert, 1989 (Box-folder 12: 2)
  - "Zaire in the International Arena," Young, Crawford, 1982 (Box-folder 12: 3)
- Printed Matter, 1951-2007 (Box 12-23)
  - Ablex Publishing Corporation, undated (Box-folder 12: 4)
  - Addis Fortune, "Understanding Somalia" series, 2007 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - American Federation of Teachers (AFT), East African Famine/Refugee Assistance Project materials, undated (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - Af Soomaali: Fasalka Afaraad, 1975 (Box-folder 12: 7)
  - Africa Confidential, articles about Somalia, Ethiopia, and Kenya, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 12: 8)
  - Africa Report
    - "The Lessons of Famine," de Waal, Alex and Omaar, Rakiya, 1992 (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - "Scientific Socialism: African Style,", 1975 (Box-folder 12: 10)
    - "Somalia: The Stateless State," Menkhaus, Kenneth and Prendergast, John, 1995 (Box-folder 12: 11)
    - "Somalia,", undated (Box-folder 12: 12)
  - "Somalia: A Fight to the Death?," Africa Watch: A Committee of Humans Rights Watch, 1992 February 13 (Box-folder 12: 13)
  - African Research and Documentation, "The Rise of Written Somali Literature," Andrzejewski, B.W., 1975 (Box-folder 12: 14)
  - African Studies Review, "Social Classes and Economic Restructuring in Pastoral Africa: Somali Notes," Samatar, Abdi Isamil, undated (Box-folder 12: 15)
  - African Survey, "Somalia: Socialist Development,", 1973 (Box-folder 12: 16)
  - Africa Today
    - "Refugees in Africa," Miller, Jake C.; "Class and Politics," Scarritt, James R. and Samoff, Joel, 1982 (Box-folder 12: 17)
    - "Somalia: The Painful Road to Reconciliation," Michaelson, Marc, 1993 (Box-folder 12: 18)
    - "Somalia's Troubled Present," Laitin, David D., 1989 (Box-folder 12: 19)
    - "U.S. Intervention in the Horn of Africa Amidst the End of the Cold War," Schraeder, Peter J., 1993 (Box-folder 12: 20)
  - African Affairs, "Cold War on the Horn of Africa," Schwab, Peter, undated (Box-folder 12: 21)
  - "The Political Party System in the Somali Republic: A Balancing-Coalitional Approach," Castagno, A. A., African Studies Center, 1964 (Box-folder 12: 22)
  - African Studies Review, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 12: 23)
  - Ahhdiga 'Usub, 1972 (Box-folder 12: 24)
  - The American Economic Review, "Cooperation, Conflict and Power in the Absence of Property Rights," Skaperdas, Stergios, 1992 (Box-folder 12: 25)
  - American Historical Review, review of Somalia: Nation in Search of a State, 1989 October (Box-folder 12: 26)
  - Amnesty International, news releases, 1987 (Box-folder 12: 27)
  - Aussenpolitik: German Foreign Affairs Review, "Soviet Military Aid to the Third World," Krause, Joachim, 1983 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Bibliography of articles and books on African society/culture, undated (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - "A Bibliography of the Somali Language and Literature," Johnson, John William, 1969 (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - Sayniska Dugsiyada Hoose: Buugga Labaad, 1992 (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - Buugga Suugaanta: Dugsiga Sare, Fasalka Afraad, undated (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - Buugga Taariikhda Dugsiyada Hoose, 1972 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - Canadian Journal of African Studies, review of Somalia: Nation in Search of a State, 1988 (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - "A 'Seamless' Transition: United States and United Nations Operations in Somalia - 1992-1993," Rosegrant, Susan and Watkins, Michael D., Case Program, John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University, 1996 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - Center for International Development and Conflict Management, University of Maryland, College Park materials, undated (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - World Fact Book, "Somalia," Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), 1991, 2000 (Box-folder 13: 10)
  - Codka Macallinka: Teacher's Voice, Issue 7, 1973 February (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - Colonial Reports: Somaliland Protectorate 1950 and 1951, 1952 (Box-folder 13: 12)
  - "Communication to the Permanent Missions of the States Members of the U.N. at the Request of the Permanent Representative of Somalia to the U.N.,", 1978 (Box-folder 13: 13)
  - Conflict, Security and Development, "Living with Statelessness: The Somali Road to Development," Bradbury, Mark, 2003 April (Box-folder 13: 14)
  - Consequences of Abyssinian Colonialism, 1979 (Box-folder 13: 15)
  - Congressional Research Service (CRS) Issue Brief, "Somalia: Operation Restore Hope and UNOSOM II," Copson, Raymond W., 1993 (Box-folder 13: 16)
  - Congressional Research Service (CRS) Report for Congress, "Somalia: Chronology of Events, June 26, 1960-October 14, 1993," Branaman, Brenda M., 1993 October 15 (Box-folder 13: 17)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) Africa Notes, "Governance and Economic Survival in Post Intervention Somalia," Menkhaus, Ken and Prendergast, John, 1995 (Box-folder 13: 18)
  - Current History
    - "Doing Harm by Doing Good?: The International Relief Effort in Somalia," de Waal, Alex and Omaar, Rakiya, 1993 May (Box-folder 13: 19)
    - "Somalia: The Wages of Failure," Bryden, Matthew, 1995 April (Box-folder 13: 21)
    - "Somalia: At War With Itself," Omaar, Rakiya, 1991 October (Box-folder 13: 20)
  - Dalka, 1967, 1969 (Box-folder 13: 22)
    "An Independent English Monthly of Current Affairs." Includes Ser. 1, Vol. 2, #10, April 1, 1967; Ser. 2, Vol. 1, #1, October 1, 1969; and Ser. 2, Vol. 1, #2, October 15, 1969.
  - Dalka, special personal issue for H. E. Mohammed Siyad Barre, President of the Republic of Somalia, Duhul, Yousuf Jama Ali, 1981 July 1 (Box-folder 13: 23)
  - Defense and Foreign Policy, "The Horn of Africa," Pytte, Alyson, 1989 May 13 (Box-folder 13: 24)
  - Development and Change, review of Somalia: Nation in Search of a State, 1990 (Box-folder 13: 25)
  - Development and Change, "Somalia: Understanding an Unconventional Economy," Jamal, Vali, 1988 (Box-folder 13: 26)
  - East-West Culture Learning Institute Language Planning Newsletter, "The Implementation and Language Planning in Somalia: A Record of Achievement," Andrzejewski, B. W., 1980 February (Box-folder 13: 27)
  - Economic Commission for Africa (ECA), summary of data on Somalia, 1975 (Box-folder 13: 28)
  - Economic Survey of Somalia: 1955-1966, Jana (Habashi), Mohamed, 1967 June (Box-folder 13: 29)
  - Somalia, "Economy," Lewis, I. M., undated (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - "Egypt Hosts an International Symposium on the Horn of Africa," Samatar, Said S., undated (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - Entwicklungsoolink, review of Somalia: Nation in Search of a State, 1988 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - Eritrean Liberation Front (People's Liberation Forces), ELF-PLF
    - "Eritrea: A Victim of U.N. Decision and of Ethiopian Aggression" and "The Eritrean People's Right to Self-Determination,", 1971, 1983 (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - "The Federal Resolution and Its Ineffectiveness,", 1983 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - Eritrea Red Cross/Crescent Society (ERCCS) and the Eritrean Relief Committee (ERC), correspondence re unity agreement, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - Ethiopia: Anatomy of a Traditional Polity, Markakis, John, 1974 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - "Second Seminar on Decentralized Political Structures for Somalia, November 16-18, 1996," report on conclusions, European Union, Somali Unit, 1996 November 29 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - "Resolutions of 31st Ordinary Session of the Council of Ministers," Executive Secretariat of the Organization of African Unity to the United Nations, 1978 (Box-folder 14: 9)
  - Fidinta Far Somaliga, 1972 (Box-folder 14: 10)
  - Foreign Affairs, "Debacle in Somalia," Clark, Jeffrey, undated (Box-folder 14: 11)
  - Foreign Policy, "Hope Restored in Somalia?," Stevenson, Jonathan, 1993 Summer (Box-folder 14: 12)
  - Foreign Affairs, "The Lessons of Somalia: Not Everything Went Wrong," Crocker, Chester A., 1995 (Box-folder 14: 13)
  - Foreign Affairs, "Somalia and the Future of Humanitarian Intervention," Clarke, Walter and Herbst, Jeffrey, 1996 (Box-folder 14: 14)
  - Foreign Affairs, "Wrong Turn in Somalia," Bolton, John R., 1994 (Box-folder 14: 15)
  - Foreign Broadcast Information Center (FBIS) reports, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 14: 16)
  - Halgan (The Struggle)
    Organ of the Somali Revolutionary Socialist Party. In Somali and English.
    - Includes No. 4 (February) and No. 7 (May), 1977 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - Includes No. 9 (July) and No. 13 (November), 1977 (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - Includes No. 15 (January), No. 16 (February), No. 21 (July), and Nos. 23-26 (September-December), 1978 (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - Includes No. 27 (January), No. 30/31 (April/May), and No. 34/35 (August/September), 1979 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Hard Choices: Critical Years in American Foreign Policy, p. 72-89, Vance, Cyrus, 1983 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Hawl iyo Hantiwadag!, undated (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - "The Crisis and Chaos in Somalia" and "U.S. Participation in Somalia Peacekeeping," Hearings Before the Sub-Committee on Africa, 1993 (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - "Economic and Security Assistance Programs in Africa," Hearing and Markup Before the Sub-Committee on Africa, 1981 (Box-folder 15: 8)
  - "Reprogramming of Military Aid to Somalia," Hearing Before the Sub-Committee on Africa, 1980 (Box-folder 15: 9)
  - "Hiin Finiin, the Poet's Favorite Horse," Hassan, Mohammed Abdille, undated (Box-folder 15: 10)
  - Horn of Africa
    - Press release, 1982 (Box-folder 15: 11)
    - Vol. 1, Nos. 1-4, 1978 (Box-folder 15: 12)
    - Vol. 3, Nos. 2-4, 1980 (Box-folder 15: 13)
    - Vol. 4, Nos. 2-3, 1981 (Box-folder 15: 14)
    - Vol. 5, Nos. 1-4, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - Vol. 6, Nos. 1-4, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - Vol. 7, No. 1, 1985 (Box-folder 16: 3)
    - "Notes on the State of the Somali State," Galaydh, Ali K., 1990 (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - "The Somali Opposition Fronts: Some Comments and Questions," Compagnon, Daniel, 1990 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - The Lost Agenda, "Human Rights and U.N. Field Operations,", 1993 (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - "The Humanitarian Crisis in Somalia: Struggle for Resources in a Divided Society," Auvinen, Juha and Kivimäki, Timo, undated (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Il Mulino, "Note Sulla Somalia: A Proposito di Conflitti Culturali," de Angelis, Enrico, 1990 (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Iftiinka-Aqoonta (Light of Education), Nos. 5 and 6, 1967 (Box-folder 16: 9)
  - Indian Ocean Newsletter, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 16: 10)
    Includes indices.
  - "Key Decisions in the Somali Intervention," Menkhaus, Ken and Ortmayer, Louis, The Institute for the Study of Diplomacy, 1995 (Box-folder 16: 11)
  - Africa Report, "Biting the Somali Bullet," International Crisis Group (ICG), 2004 May 4 (Box-folder 16: 12)
  - Africa Report, "Counter-terrorism in Somalia: Losing Hearts and Minds?" and "Somalia's Islamists," International Crisis Group (ICG), 2005 (Box-folder 16: 13)
  - International news and newspaper clippings on Somalia, 1969-1992 (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - Journal of the Anglo-Somali Society (Warsodaha Urarka Ingiriiska iyo Soomaalida), 1992 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - Journal of International Affairs, "The Andrew Willington Cordier Essay: Arms and Aggression in the Horn of Africa," Watson, Paul, 1986 (Box-folder 17: 3)
  - The Journal of Modern African Studies, "From Peacekeeping to Peace Enforcement: The UN Operation in Somalia," Thakur, Ramesh, 1994 (Box-folder 17: 4)
  - The Journal of Modern African Studies, "Somali Nationalism: Its Origins and Future," Sheikh-Abdi, Abdi, 1978 (Box-folder 17: 5)
  - Journal of Political Economy, "Anarchy and Its Breakdown," Hirshleifer, Jack, 1955 (Box-folder 17: 6)
  - Juqraafi: Fasalka Saddexaad, 1977 (Box-folder 17: 7)
  - Life and Peace Review, "Conflict, Peacebuilding and International Aid: The State of Debate,", 1995 (Box-folder 17: 8)
  - "L'Italia e l'Economia Somala dal 1950 ad Oggi," Triulzi, Umberto, 1976 (Box-folder 17: 9)
  - Map of Somalia and Djibouti, undated (Box-folder 17: 10)
  - Middle East Policy, "Getting Out vs. Getting Through: U.S. and U.N. Policies in Somalia," Menkhaus, Ken, 1994 (Box-folder 17: 11)
  - Ministry of Information and National Guidance (Ethiopia), 1977-1978 (Box-folder 17: 12-13)
    Includes "PMAC Chairman Address to the Nation…," April 12, 1977; "PMAC Chairman's Visit to Cuba," April 21-27, 1978; "Speech delivered by PMAC Chairman," September 12, 1978; "Statement by Comrade Lt. Colonel Mengistu Hailemariam, Chairman Provisional Military Government of Ethiopia to the 14th Assembly by Heads of State of the O.A.U.," July 2-5, 1977; and "The National Revolutionary War in the North," June 7, 1978.
  - Ministry of Information and National Guidance Mogadishu Somali Democratic Republic
    - "Agriculture in the Service of the Nation: More Production with More Efforts,", 1974 (Box-folder 17: 14)
    - Beautiful Somalia, 1971, 1978 (Box-folder 17: 15)
    - The Disastrous Damages of Ethiopian Aggression, 1978 (Box-folder 17: 16)
    - Somalia Today: General Information, 1970 (Box-folder 17: 17)
    - My Country and My People: The Collected Speeches of Major General Mohammed Siad Barre, President, the Supreme Revolutionary Council, Somali Democratic Republic, 1971 October (Box-folder 17: 18)
    - My Country and My People: Selected Speeches of Jaalle Siyad, 1969-1979, 1979 October (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - New Era, Year 1, No. 1 (February) and Year 3, No. 27 (September/October), 1973, 1975 (Box-folder 18: 2)
    - "Our Revolutionary Education: Its Strategy and Objectives,", 1974 June (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - Revolutionary Somalia, 1978 October (Box-folder 18: 4)
    - "Two Years of Progress: Somalia Under the Revolution,", 1971 October (Box-folder 18: 5)
  - A Minority Rights Group reports, 1991 (Box-folder 18: 6)
    Contains "Somalia: A Nation in Turmoil" and two copies of a profile on Somalia.
  - "Nationalism, Peasant Politics and the Emergence of a Vanguard Front in Eritrea," Gebre-Medhin, Jordan, 1987 (Box-folder 18: 7)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1978 (Box-folder 18: 8)
  - News items, Somalia, 2002-2005 (Box-folder 18: 9)
    Printed copies of web pages and articles about Somalia.
  - Newspaper clippings, Ethiopia-Somalia War, 1977 (Box-folder 18: 10)
  - Newspaper clippings, Nigeria coup of December 31, 1983, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 18: 11)
  - Northeast African Studies, "Ethnic Identity and Social Change Among Oromo Refugees in the Horn of Africa," Braukämper, Ulrich, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - The Translation of Culture: Essays to E.E. Evans-Pritchard, "Nuer Kingship: A Re-Examination," Gough, Kathleen, 1971 (Box-folder 19: 2)
  - Permanent Mission of the Somali Democratic Republic to the U.N, statements by Jalle Dr. Abdurahman Jama Barre to the United Nations, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 19: 3)
  - Play About Sayid Abdille Hassan, undated (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - Northeast African Studies, "Policy Dilemmas in the Horn of Africa: Contradictions in the U.S.-Somalia Relationship," Schraeder, Peter J. and Rosati, Jerel A., 1987 (Box-folder 19: 5)
  - Population Policy Compendium, 1984 (Box-folder 19: 6)
    Includes reports by the United Nations on Somalia and Ethiopia.
  - Consequences of Somalia's Aggression, Press Department, Ministry of Information and National Guidance (Ethiopia), 1978 July (Box-folder 19: 7)
  - The Principles of Somali, Warsama, Solomon and Abraham, R.C., 1951 (Box-folder 19: 8)
  - Somalia and the World, Vols. 1 and 2, circa 1979 (Box-folder 19: 9)
    Published proceedings of the International Symposium held in Mogadishu, October 15-21, 1979. Topics discussed include: "Toward International Somali Studies," "Language, Linguistics and Literature," "Revolutionary Transformations," and "Self-Determination and Conflict in the Horn of Africa."
  - Proceedings of the Second International Congress of Somali Studies, Volume 3: Aspects of Development, 1983 (Box-folder 19: 10)
  - Publishers Weekly, 1986 (Box-folder 19: 11)
  - "A Questioneer on African Unity,", undated (Box-folder 19: 12)
  - Qaffi Wacnaa ee reer Sejwaan, Brecht, B., undated (Box-folder 19: 13)
  - Lives Lost, Lives Saved: Excess Mortality and the Impact of Health Interventions in the Somali Emergency, Refugee Policy Group, 1994 November (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Research and Information Center on Eritrea (R.I.C.E.), 1984 (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - Returned Peace Corps Volunteers/Somalia Newsletter, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - Review of African Political Economy (ROAPE) (Box-folder 20:)
    - "Briefings: Somalia: Conflict Within and Against the Military Regime," Gilkes, Patrick, 1989 (Box-folder 20: 4)
    - "New Hope for Somalia? The Building Block Approach," Bryden, Matt, 1999 March (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - "Somalia: Militarism, Warlordism or Democracy?," Adam, Hussein M., 1992 (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - "Somaliland: Choosing Politics Over Violence,", 2003 (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - Sahanka Tacabdhalka Warshadaha 1975, "Industrial Production Survey,", 1977 September (Box-folder 20: 8)
  - School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS) Review, "Nationalism Unbound: The Horn of Africa Revisited," Ottaway, Marina, 1992 (Box-folder 20: 9)
  - Sheeko la Riwaayadeeyey, 1978 (Box-folder 20: 10)
  - Somali Democratic Republic
    - "Annual Development Plan,", 1985 December (Box-folder 20: 11)
    - "Annual Development Plan,", 1990 (Box-folder 20: 12)
    - "National Accounts Aggregates: 1977-1988,", 1989 (Box-folder 20: 13)
    - "Performance of the Somali Economy, 1988,", 1989 (Box-folder 20: 14)
    - The Portion of Somali Territory Under Ethiopian Colonization, 1974 June (Box-folder 20: 15)
    - "Three Year Plan, 1979-1981," State Planning Commission (Box-folder 20: 16)
  - "Information about Somalia, the Bank, and the Investment Opportunities in Somalia," The Somali Development Bank, 1969 April (Box-folder 20: 17)
  - "Administrative Efficiency and Administrative Language in Somalia," Omar, Osman Mohammed, The Somali Institute of Development Administration and Management, 1976 September (Box-folder 20: 18)
  - "Administrative Changes in Somalia (October 1971-October 1972)," Somali Institute of Public Administration, 1972 October 1 (Box-folder 20: 19)
  - Somali National Movement (SNM)
    - Press release and policies, 1981 (Box-folder 20: 20)
    - Somali Horizon (Box-folder 20: 21)
      - 1986-1987 (Box-folder 21: 1)
        Includes Nos. 1-3 (Spring, July, and August), 1986 and No. 8 (August/September), 1987.
      - 1988-1989 (Box-folder 21: 2)
        Includes No. 10 (June-August), 1988 and No. 11 (January-April), 1989.
  - The Somali Republic and African Unity, undated (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - Short Term Development Programme, 1968-1970, Somali Republic Planning Commission, 1968 August (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Somali, Tigray and Oromo Resistance Monitor (STORM) (Box-folder 21:)
    - 1981 (Box-folder 21: 5)
      Vol. 1, No. 2 (March), No. 3 (June), and No. 4 (October).
    - 1982 (Box-folder 21: 6)
      Vol. 2, No. 1 (March), No. 2 (May), and No. 4 (December).
    - 1983 (Box-folder 21: 7)
      Vol. 3, No. 1 (March), No. 2 (June), No. 3 (November), and No. 4 (December).
    - 1984 (Box-folder 21: 8)
      Vol. 4, No. 1 (March) and No. 2 (July).
  - Somali Update, undated (Box-folder 21: 9)
  - "Somalia: Central Statistics Office,", 1989 (Box-folder 21: 10)
  - "Somalia: Collapse of the State and the Civil War,", undated (Box-folder 21: 11)
  - "Hope Restored? Humanitarian Aid in Somalia, 1990-1994," Sommer, John G. (Somalia Humanitarian Aid Study), Refugee Policy Group, 1994 November (Box-folder 21: 12)
  - Somalia: Productive Sectors of the Economy, 1985 (Box-folder 21: 13)
  - Somalia: Statistical Abstract, 1970, 1971 November (Box-folder 21: 14)
  - Somalia: The Problem Child of Africa, Wolde-Mariam, Mesfin, 1977 September (Box-folder 21: 15)
  - "Somaliland: One Thorn Bush at a Time," Omaar, Rakiya, undated (Box-folder 21: 16)
  - Stanford-Berkeley Joint Center for African Studies newsletter, 1982 (Box-folder 21: 17)
  - Stars and Stripes, "U.S. Moves Carrier Off Coast of Somalia,", 2007 (Box-folder 21: 18)
  - Statement by H. E. Col. Dr. Feleke Gedle-Giorgis, Minister for Foreign Affairs of Socialist Ethiopia, during United Nations General Assembly, 1978 (Box-folder 21: 19)
  - Statement by spokesman for United Nations Secretary General, 2005 (Box-folder 21: 20)
  - A Study of Decentralized Political Structures for Somalia: A Menu of Options, 1995 August (Box-folder 21: 21)
  - Summary of World Broadcasts (SWB), 1977-1981 (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - "Support the Just Cause of the Ethiopian Peoples,", undated (Box-folder 22: 2)
  - Suugannta: Fasalka Lixaad, 1976 (Box-folder 22: 3)
  - Taariikh: Fasalka Shanaad, 1978 (Box-folder 22: 4)
  - Taariikhdii Daraawiishta iyo Sayid Maxamed Cabdulle Xasan (1895-1921), 1976 (Box-folder 22: 5)
  - "The Theory of Industrial Organization," Tirole, Jean, 1989 (Box-folder 22: 6)
  - Times Literary Supplement, de Waal, Alex, 1995 December (Box-folder 22: 7)